Guide to the Blodgett Family Account Books, 1895-1976
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
Blodgett Family Account Books
1895-1976
Blodgett, Minnie A. Cumnock, 1862-1931
Hadley, Katherine Blodgett, 1898-1980
2.4 cubic feet (3 boxes)
Archives and Special Collections Library, Vassar College Libraries
A collection of account books relating to the Blodgett family, primarily describing household affairs and expenses. The majority of the books were kept by Katherine Blodgett Hadley (VC 1920), two of the books were kept by Minnie Cumnock Blodgett (VC 1884), and the final book is undated and entitled “Gregory and Vail Hay Book” and inscribed with “From the [Dear?] Library, Fishkill Village.”
Biographical Note
Minnie A. (Cumnock) Blodgett (1862-1931) was a Vassar graduate, Class of 1884, and was later a member of the Board of Trustees. She married John W. Blodgett in 1895 and had two children: John W. Blodgett, Jr. and Katherine (Blodgett) Hadley. Katherine followed in her mother's footsteps, graduating from Vassar in 1920. She served on the Board of Trustees from 1942 to 1954 and was Chairman of the Board from 1945 to 1952.
Scope and Content Note
The collection consists of forty-four account books relating to the Blodgett family, primarily describing household affairs and expenses. Forty-one volumes were kept by Katherine Blodgett Hadley (VC 1920), two volumes were kept by Minnie Cumnock Blodgett (VC 1884), and the final volumes is undated, but the first page is embossed with “Lindmark’s Book Shop, Poughkeepsie, New York,” a business that was established in 1912. It is entitled “Gregory and Vail Hay Book” and inscribed with “From the [Dear?] Library, Fishkill Village.”
Collection is arranged chronologically.
Access
This collection is open for research according to the
regulations of the Vassar College Archives and Special Collections Library
without any additional restrictions.
Subject Headings
Names:
Blodgett family
Subjects:
Households--Economic aspects--United States
Document Types:
Account books
VCL Categories:
Family; Local History
Encoding Information
Encoded by Emma Gronbeck, June 2023.
Acquisition Information
The Katherine Blodgett Hadley account books were the gift of Barbara Hadley Stanton (VC 1957), December 1980.
Provenance of the Minnie A. Cumnock Blodgett and "Gregory and Vail Hay Book" volumes is unknown.
Container List
- Minnie A. (Cumnock) Blodgett - Account Books, Vol. 1, 1895-1904 (Box 1)
- Minnie A. (Cumnock) Blodgett - Account Books, Vo1. 2, 1907-1912 (Box 1)
- "Gregory and Vail Hay Book, from [Dear?] Library, Fishkill Village" - Account Book, circa 1910s (Box 1)
- Katherine (Blodgett) Hadley - Account Books
  - Vol. 1, 1937 (Box 1)
  - Vol. 2, 1938 (Box 1)
  - Vol. 3, 1939 (Box 1)
  - Vol. 4, 1940 (Box 2)
  - Vol. 5, 1941 (Box 2)
  - Vol. 6, 1942 (Box 2)
  - Vol. 7, 1943 (Box 2)
  - Vol. 8, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Vol. 9, 1945 (Box 2)
  - Vol. 10-11, 1946 (Box 2)
  - Vol. 12, 1947 (Box 2)
  - Vol. 13, 1948 (Box 2)
  - Vol. 14, 1949 (Box 2)
  - Vol. 15, 1950 (Box 2)
  - Vol. 16, 1951 (Box 2)
  - Vol. 17, 1952 (Box 2)
  - Vol. 18, 1953 (Box 2)
  - Vol. 19, 1954 (Box 2)
  - Vol. 20, 1955 (Box 2)
  - Vol. 21, 1956 (Box 2)
  - Vol. 22, 1957 (Box 2)
  - Vol. 23, 1958 (Box 3)
  - Vol. 24, 1959 (Box 3)
  - Vol. 25, 1960 (Box 3)
  - Vol. 26, 1961 (Box 3)
  - Vol. 27, 1962 (Box 3)
  - Vol. 28, 1963 (Box 3)
  - Vol. 29, 1964 (Box 3)
  - Vol. 30, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Vol. 31, 1966 (Box 3)
  - Vol. 32, 1967 (Box 3)
  - Vol. 33, 1968 (Box 3)
  - Vol. 34, 1969 (Box 3)
  - Vol. 35, 1970 (Box 3)
  - Vol. 36, 1971 (Box 3)
  - Vol. 37, 1972 (Box 3)
  - Vol. 38, 1973 (Box 3)
  - Vol. 39, 1974 (Box 3)
  - Vol. 40, 1975 (Box 3)
  - Vol. 41, 1976 (Box 3)